<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on Nikhil Raghav</title>
    <link>/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on Nikhil Raghav</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© Nikhil 2025</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Browser is watching</title>
      <link>/posts/palemoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/palemoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPD : These views are really old, I still use firefox, you can stop updating firefox by making changes to about:policies or can use icecat or librewolf. But firefox is by far the most advanced and private browser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love minimal software and always try to minimize bloat on whatever system I use. I also like to read too many blogs on internet but you don&amp;rsquo;t need a power hungry and feature rich browser to &amp;ldquo;just read blogs&amp;rdquo;. So recently, I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EBWy1d-JE6A&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; video introducing &lt;a href=&#34;https://hacktivis.me/projects/badwolf&#34;&gt;BadWolf&lt;/a&gt;, which is a minimal &lt;a href=&#34;https://webkitgtk.org&#34;&gt;WebKitGTK+&lt;/a&gt; based browser that has two very accessible buttons to toggle javascript and images on a webpage and one simple download manager. I know there is much more going on behind the scenes, but this is what that meets the eye first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private search engine in 5 minutes</title>
      <link>/posts/searx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/searx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every non privacy respecting search engine out there logs your search history to profile you and target you with more personalised ads, sometimes that also leads to a self created filter bubble.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://searx.me&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Searx&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a metasearch engine available under GPL 3, which compiles search results from more than 70 search engines. Fun fact is you can deploy it locally and enjoy searching from your customised search engine. I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
